Guide to the Western Pennsylvania Conservancy Records and Photographs, 1885-2006 AIS.1999.13
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Western Pennsylvania Conservancy Records
1845-2006
1936-2004
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Western Pennsylvania Conservancy
AIS.1999.13
81.93 Linear Feet (61 boxes)
The Western Pennsylvania Conservancy (WPC) is a non-profit organization created to set aside and preserve tracts of land from large-scale commercial development. The land is usually deemed significant for its ecological, historical, or scenic importance. This collection contains the records and photogrpahs of the WPC. The records of their preservation efforts include deeds, grants, and land transfers along with correspondence and legal documents. The photographs include prints of various sizes, negatives, 35mm slides, glass plate negatives, and lantern slides, depicting land which the WPC has worked to transform into some of today's most utilized parks, nature reserves, protected state game lands, and historical sites. Furthermore, the photographs document the WPC's efforts to beautify communities throughout Western Pennsylvania with the creation of gardens and greenways.
History
The Western Pennsylvania Conservancy (WPC) began as the Greater Pittsburgh Parks Association (GPPA) in 1932. The organization's first projects included transforming a barren stretch of land lying parallel to Bigelow Boulevard into a park (resulting in Frank Curto Park) and expanding Frick Park in Pittsburgh's East End. However, through the Depression and World War II, funding and interest for the Parks Association remained low, and accomplishments were sporadic.
By 1951 the GPPA reestablished itself as the Western Pennsylvania Conservancy and began purchasing large tracts of land from willing individuals and communities. The next two decades were spent merging these properties and forming some of today's most utilized Western Pennsylvania parks. McConnell's Mill represents one of the first of these efforts. From 1945 and culminating in 1974, the WPC set aside the land for McConnell's Mill in Lawrence County, ultimately designating it a Natural Historic Park. In the early 1950s, the WPC began to attain the land that would later comprise the Ferncliff Peninsula. This project would widen in scope throughout the next fifteen years, resulting in the establishment of the Ohiopyle State Park in Fayette County. Between 1959 and 1964, the WPC also created Muddy Creek, the central focus of Moraine State Park. The year 1963 marked a watershed year for the WPC. Much of the land for Raccoon Creek State Park was acquired and Edgar Kaufmann, Jr. entrusted the WPC with the world famous Frank Lloyd Wright home, Fallingwater.
Beyond these accomplishments, the WPC was also instrumental in consolidating the land that would encompass Laurel Ridge and Oil Creek. The WPC worked simultaneously augmenting Cherry Run, McCoy Farm, and Conneaut Marsh, all protected state game lands.
Outside of land acquisitions, transfers, and the maintenance of Fallingwater, the WPC also played a large role in preserving historical sites. The Old Stone House Village, a nineteenth century stopover point for mail carriers, was restored and remains a Butler County attraction. Also, in keeping with the theme of the Greater Pittsburgh Parks Association, the WPC has worked with community organizations in and around Pittsburgh to plant and maintain gardens found along roadways, neighborhoods, and businesses.
Since 1932, the WPC has acquired over 85,000 acres of land, with the stated goal of pushing this total to 110,000 acres by 2010. This land has then been transferred to the state, maintained by the conservancy, or sold to private individuals under the condition that it remains free of commercial development. Today, the Western Pennsylvania Conservancy boasts a small full-time staff and over 9,000 members, all of whom want to conserve the natural and cultural heritage of Western Pennsylvania.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains the records and photographs of the Western Pennsylvania Conservancy (WPC).
The record series reflects the efforts of the WPC to buy and transfer land, some of which has led to the creation of the state's most visited parks. The series contains records from the acquisition of land necessary for McConnell's Mill, Ohiopyle, Ferncliff, Moraine, and Raccoon Creek State Parks. The records also document restoration projects, including the Old Stone House Village and the Johnston Tavern. The vast majority of records in this series date between the early 1950s and the late 1970s.
The photograph series contains both black and white and color prints of various sizes, 35mm slides, negatives, glass plate negatives, and lantern slides. While the earliest images date back to 1885 and include glass plate negatives of the Ohiopyle region, the majority of images date between the early 1950s and the early 2000s. Prominent among the photographs in this series are McConnell's Mill, Ohiopyle, and Raccoon Creek State Parks. Historic preservation projects are also very well documented, particularly the Burke Building. Finally, the photograph series depicts the WPC's ongoing efforts to protect and maintain greenways throughout Western Pennsylvania with the help of local communities.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of the Western Pennsylvania Conservancy on June 21, 1999. Photographs were acquired in May 2013.
Previous Citation
Western Pennsylvania Conservancy Records, 1885-2006, AIS.1999.13, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Stone House (Butler, Pa.); Raccoon Creek State Park (Pa.); Color negatives; Moraine State Park Watershed (Pa.); Color prints (Photographs); Moraine State Park (Pa.); Negatives (Photographic); Ohiopyle State Park (Pa.); Lantern slides; McConnell's Mill State Park (Pa.); Color slides; Frick Park (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Black-and-white negatives; Frank Curto Park (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Black-and-white prints (Photographs); Parks -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Parks -- Pennsylvania; Associations; Environment; Greater Pittsburgh Parks Association; Western Pennsylvania Conservancy
- Records, 1845-1975; 1932-1975; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Most of the records in this series are comprised of purchases made by the WPC from individuals that have not been consolidated into a park or incorporated into a game preserve. These documents are primarily legal in nature and are identified by the county in which the property lies. Particularly large tracts that took longer to purchase and involve more paperwork are housed in their own folders and are identified by the individual. This land has remained under the auspices of the WPC, has been transferred to the state, or resold with the intent of preserving its scenic, cultural, and/or historic value.
  Beyond land purchases, transfers, and deeds, the record collection also features projects dedicated to historic preservation. The largest of these efforts was the Old Stone House Village in Butler County (Boxes 30-31). The Johnston Tavern restoration project, albeit smaller than the Old Stone House village, is contained herein (Box 17).
  The record collection also holds various correspondences that details political jockeying on virtually all of the above topics. Some of the oldest documents in the collection are those regarding the Greater Pittsburgh Parks Association, with letters and meeting minutes dating back to the early 1930s (Boxes 15-16).
  The WPC, as a non-profit agency, relies on funding from many sources to conduct their efforts. The items detailing Project 70, a lobbying effort to secure $70 million in state and federal funding by 1970, was the largest of such efforts (see Boxes 22-23).
  Despite being a cornerstone of WPC organizational growth and identity, the record collection does not currently contain records or items pertaining to Fallingwater except in passing mention or in brief statements. While there are deeds from private owners extending back to the nineteenth century, the vast majority of records in this collection date between the early 1950s and the late 1970s.
  - Donegal Twp., Westmoreland County Transfers, 1965-1977 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
  - Mt. Streams Report and Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - Laurel Highlands Taskforce, 1968-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Westmoreland County Transfers, 1926-1974 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Somerset County Land Surveys, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Seven Springs: Proposed Airport Items, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Somerset County Transfers, 1947-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania Turnpike Commission, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Laurel Ridge: Condemned Properties and Maps, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Shade and Ux Property Transfer, 1959-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
  - Greene County Project, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Energy Development in Greene County, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Land Policy Project, Budgets, Funding, and Contracts, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Land Policy Project, Art Dalis Memos, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - LPP Energy Conversion Facilities Panel, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Land Policy Project, Land Use Materials, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Land Policy Project, LUPSAC BOR, 1972-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  - Land Policy Project, PEC, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Land Policy Project, TMS Notes, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Land Policy Project, TMS Paper, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Land Policy Project, Projects Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Land Policy Project, Projects Correspondence, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Land Policy Project, Publications, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - A Land Use Program For Pennsylvania, Volume I: An Interim Policy Guide, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Land Policy Project, Overviews, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Land Policy Project, TMS Paper, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Burrell Twp. Indiana County Transfers, 1961-1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Oaks Point Realty Co., Correspondence, Deeds, and Appraisals, 1923-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
  - Oaks Point Realty Co., Abstracts and Certificates of Title, 1907-1969 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Peoples Natural Gas Co., Burrell Twp., Indiana County, 1923-1973 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Chestnut Ridge, Derry Fairfield Twps., Westmoreland County, 1896-1968 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Garfield Refractories Co., Fairfield Twp., Westmoreland County, 1901-1972 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - Chestnut Ridge Property, Westmoreland County Transfers, 1875-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
  - Correspondance: Conemaugh Gorge and H.I. Miller, 1968-1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Leuffer Est., Chestnut Ridge, Westmoreland County, Property, 1850-1973 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sullivan Heirs, 1962-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - John Buchanan, 2 to 3 Acres, Pulaski Twp., Lawrence County, 1963-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Humphrey, C.L. Ross House, Jennings Reserve Area, 1964-1979 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Jennings Reserve Lease With Penna. Dept. of Education, WPC, 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pulaski Twp., Lawrence County Transfers, 1961-1976 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Brady Twp., Butler County Transfers, 1922-1971 (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
  - Slippery Rock Veterans Club, Butler County, 1856-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
  - Schmidt Property Transfer, Blazing Star Prairie, 1952-1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Pulaski Twp., Butler County Transfers, 1963-1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Perry, Hidden Lake, 1856-1979 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Helsel Property Land Transfer, 1935-1979 (Box 4, Folder 16-18)
  - Ligonier Twp., Westmoreland County Land Transfer, 1934-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Raydure File, 1967-1976 (Box 5, Folder 2-3)
  - Miami Oil Producers Inc., Correspondence, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4-6)
  - Miami Oil Producers Inc., Bob Van Groottenruel, 1956-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Miami Oil Producers Inc., Maps and Surveys, 1966-1973 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - National Forge Tract, Allegheny River, 1970-1973 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Raydure File #2, 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Cropp Farms Inc., Cross Reference, 1971-1976 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
  - Cropp Farms Inc., 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - National Forge Transfer, 1971-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Arthur S. Beach, Allegheny River, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Ice Control, Oil City, Corps of Engineers, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Penn DOT Environmental Action Plan (Draft), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - B & R Lumber Company: Deeds and Leases, 1931-1983 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Ellwood-Wampum Rod Gun Club Property, 1951-1956 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Interim Report; Blazing Star Land Acquisition, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - B & R Lumber, General File, 1978-1984 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - B & R Survey and Maps, 1957-1979 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - B & R Lumber Company, Insurance, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - B & R Lumber Company, Leases, 1978-1980 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Bixel Property, 1946-1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - B & R Lumber Company, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - B & R Lumber, Mellon Bank Correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - B & R Lumber, Bank Statements, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - B & R Lumber, 1979-1981 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Beatty Tract, Transfer to Penna. Game commission, 1960-1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Laurel Hill State Park, Conveyed to Commonwealth, 1967-1976 (Box 7, Folder 2-6)
  - Working Papers on Blair Estates and Properties, 1902-1967 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Mountain Streams, Miscellaneous Information, 1971-1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Mountain Streams, Uncapher Appraisals, 1953-1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Mountain Streams, Oil Gas Lease Information, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Mountain Streams, Negotiating Agent, Glenn Cook, 1972-1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Blair Work Papers, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Mountain Streams (Former HAH File), 1964-1971 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Mountain Streams, Comp. Sales, 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Plot Plans from Laurel Ridge Files, 1845-1966 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Mountain Streams Forest Management, 1959-1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Mountain Streams, Correspondence and Tax Data, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Mountain Streams Snowmobile Trails, 1972-1974 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Westmoreland County Transfers and Titles, 1967-1974 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Blair Property, Westmoreland and Somerset Counties, 1967-1974 (Box 7, Folder 20-21)
  - Donegal Twp. Westmoreland County, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Somerset County Land, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Blair Trust Agreements, 1970 (Items from 1901-1903) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - BOR Proposal For Mountain Streams, Stage 1, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Blazing Star Documents, 1960-1962 (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
  - Raccoon Creek Inventories and Legal Arrangements, 1962-1963 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Raccoon Reserve and Little Beaver Creek, 1961-1963 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Right of Way Project, 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Fallingwater Shelter Plan, 1963-1967 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Arthur E. Braun Shelter, 1963-1967 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Wildflower Reserve, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Beaver Creek, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Little Beaver River, Correspondence, Publicity, and Articles, 1961-1962 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Little Beaver River, Property Transfers and Correspondence, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Hickory House Costs (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Rights to Stewart Township, 1963-1964 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Ohiopyle Complaints, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Howard Swartz, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Robert L. Spence, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Francis R. Campbell, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ruth Richardson, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Chandler P. Pierce, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Mildred E. Burnsworth, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Ross Bryner, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Charles Shipley, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Ohiopyle Outing, 1959-1962 (Box 9, Folder 11-14)
  - Mr. Zehner's Notes of Ohiopyle Outing, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - State Tour-Ohiopyle, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Ohiopyle Falls Overlook Dedication, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Properties Owned-Ohiopyle Summary, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Ohiopyle State Park Transfer, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Ohiopyle Economic Development, 1963-1968 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Ohiopyle Economic Development, 1963-1968 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Complaints-Fayette County Assemblymen, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Ohiopyle Land Deed-Hotel Ferncliff, 1951-1964 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Ohiopyle Ferncliff Park Property, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Youghiogheny River Bike Trail, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Muddy Creek, Coal, Alford Report and Dam Site Studies, 1953-1959 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Muddy Creek Topographical Information, 1955-1962 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mineral Appraisals, Final Report, 1962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Muddy Creek, Lake Arthur, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Muddy Creek, Portersville Station Gorge, 1949-1954 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Dr. F.W. Preston, General Correspondence on Muddy Creek, 1950-1959 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Yellow Copy Correspondences, 1964-1966 (Box 10, Folder 7-20)
  - Outgoing Correspondences with Dr. Charles Lewis, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 21-22)
  - Moraine Park Maps and Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Muddy Creek Publicity, Park Studies, Correspondence, and Maps, 1957-1963 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Muddy Creek: Various Studies, 1958-1963 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Moraine and Muddy Creek, Miscellaneous Items, 1962-1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Muddy Creek Correspondence and Studies, 1959-1967 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Muddy Creek, Planning and Projects, 1957-1962 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Butler County Planning and Maps, 1960 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Muddy Creek Drainage Contracts, Reports, and Slippery Rock, 1951-1962 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Muddy Creek Assessment, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Muddy Creek Correspondence, Contracts, and Bulletins, 1959-1961 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Muddy Creek, Notes, Projects, and Finances, 1957-1962 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Real Estate Tax Schedules, 1953-1957 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Finance Articles and Brochures for PA Parks, 1957-1962 (Box 11, Folder 14-15)
  - Butler County Properties, 1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Brady Township Properties, 1952-1960 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Garber Property, Franklin Twp., Butler County, 1954-1958 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Currie Property, Franklin Twp., Butler County, 1895-1959 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Kranz Property, Franklin Twp., Butler County, 1936-1959 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
  - Lackovic Property, Muddy Creek Twp., Butler County, 1957-1959 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - McBride Property, Brady Twp., Butler County, 1948-1959 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - McBride Property, Franklin Twp., Butler County, 1955-1959 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - McKim Property, Brady Twp., Butler County, 1953-1959 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Pizor Property, Worth Twp., Butler County, 1952-1959 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Preston Property, Worth, Muddy Creek, and Franklin Twps., Butler County, 1951-1959 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Preston Property, Franklin, Worth, and Muddy Creek Twp., Butler County, Nealy, Worth Twp., Butler County, 1953-1959 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Rothey Property, Granklin Twp., Butler County, 1957 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Shannon Property, Franklin Twp., Butler County, 1955-1956 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Shaw Property, Worth Muddy Creek Twps., Butler County, 1952-1959 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Thompson Property, Franklin Twp., Butler County, 1951-1959 (Box 12, Folder 15-16)
  - Van Kirk Property, Franklin Twp., Butler County, 1951-1958 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - West Property, 25 Acres, Franklin Twp., Butler County, 1954-1957 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Reader Copies, July to December, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 19-22)
  - Reader Copies, July to December, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 23-28)
  - Reader Copies, January to June, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
  - Reader Copies, July to December, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4-7)
  - Reader Copies, January to June, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 8-15)
  - Route 8 Complex (Acreage Allocated to Each Project, Etc.), 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Route 8 Complex, Aerial Photos and Survey, 1962-1964 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Route 8 Complex, Current Projects (Old Stone House Final Costs), 1966 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Route 8 Complex, (Arboretum) Moraine Extension, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Route 8 Complex, Current Projects, Stone House Village, 1967-1968 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Route 8 Complex, Strip Mining Reclamation, Rte. 528, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Route 8 Complex, Relocation of Rte. 528 226 Rte. 8 Intersection, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Ferncliff, Current Projects, Water Supply, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Badger Property, Lawrence County, 1952-1958 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bennett Property, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Slippery Rock, Clelland, Henschel, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Dreschel Property, Lawrence County, 1945-1956 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Milton Few Property, Slippery Rock Twp., Lawrence County, 1952-1956 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Cleland Property, Perry Twp., Lawrence County, 1951-1960 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - WPC, Slippery Rock, 1947-1953 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Hartman Property, Slippery Rock Twp., Lawrence County, 1940-1959 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Helschel Property, Slippery Rock Twp., Lawrence County, 1954-1959 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Hartman Properties, 1944-1956 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Hughes Property, Perry Twp., 1951-1956 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Jones Property, Lawrence County, 1944-1956 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Plans, McConnell's Mill Property, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Jones Property, Perry Twp., Lawrence County, 1946-1955 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Kildoo Property, 1946-1947 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Lawrence County Properties, 1953-1956 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Robert E. Hogue Property, Slippery Rock Twp., Lawrence County, 1946-1956 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - William T. Hogue Property, Slippery Rock Twp., Lawrence County, 1928-1956 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Document, Retired to Fallingwater, Undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - McConnell's Mill Property, Slippery Rock Twp., Lawrence County, 1944-1958 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Slippery Rock Article By Edmund W. Arthur, 1945-1946 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Slippery Rock Signs, 1951-1954 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Stewart Property, Perry Twp., Lawrence County, 1952-1956 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - St. Clair Property, Perry Twp., Lawrence County, 1953-1956 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Slippery Rock Muddy Creek Projects, 1952-1954 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - McConnell's Mill Injury Articles, 1951-1955 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Slippery Rock Muddy Creek, 1951-1954 (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
  - McConnell's Mill Fund, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
  - Muddy Creek Contributions, 1951-1952 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - State Negotiations Regarding Slippery Rock, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - WPC Finance Records and Information, 1954-1957 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - GPPA Correspondence, 1932-1939 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - GPPA Projects, 1934-1939 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - GPPA Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, 1931-1933 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - GPPA Correspondence and Financial Notices, 1931-1932 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - GPPA Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, 1932 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - GPPA Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - GPPA Correspondence, 1932-1935 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - GPPA Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - GPPA Correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Parks Association, 1934-1937 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Greater Pittsburgh Parks Assn., General Correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Greater Pittsburgh Parks Assn., 1940 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Greater Pittsburgh Parks Assn., 1932-1940 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Loose Documents, Greater Pittsburgh Parks Assn., 1932-1945 (Box 16, Folder 5-7)
  - McConnell's Mill, Greater Pittsburgh Parks Assn., 1944-1945 (Box 16, Folder 8)